<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Nynim.org]]></title>
  <link href="http://nynim.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nynim.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-05T21:45:35-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://nynim.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tony Duckles]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Mr. Money Mustache: From Zero to Hero in One Blog Post]]></title>
<link href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2013/02/22/getting-rich-from-zero-to-hero-in-one-blog-post/"/>
<updated>2013-03-03T15:07:14-06:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2013/03/03/mr-money-mustache-from-zero-to-hero-in-one-blog-post</id>
<category term="Finance" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago, one of my friends introduced me to this blog:
<a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/">Mr. Money Mustache: Early Retirement through Badassity</a>.
(<em>The blog title is sheer awesome-ness!</em>) I quickly fell in-love with nearly
everything he was writing about.  Lots of great financial and lifestyle advice
there.</p>

<p>He&#39;s been able to put to clear words what I&#39;ve been starting to realize lately:</p>

<blockquote><p>The bottom line is this: by focusing on happiness itself, you can lead a much better life than those who focus on convenience, luxury, and following the lead of the financially illiterate herd that is the TV-ad-absorbing Middle Class of the United States today (and most of the other rich countries).  Happiness comes from many sources, but none of these sources involve car or purse upgrades. No matter what the herd or the TV set tells you, this is the truth.</p></blockquote>

<p>Living within your means and cutting-back on needless spending means lower
monthly expenses. By cutting thoses recurring expenses, you&#39;re able to save
more money.  The more money you save, the more compounding interest and
investing works in your favor. By learning to live more frugally, you&#39;re
changing your <strong>lifestyle and mindset</strong> and you end-up not <em>needing</em> as much
money for your post-retirement lifestyle. It becomes this snowball effect and
you may even be able to <a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2012/01/13/the-shockingly-simple-math-behind-early-retirement/">retire a lot earlier than you expected</a>.</p>
<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://nynim.org/blog/2013/03/03/mr-money-mustache-from-zero-to-hero-in-one-blog-post/">&#9875; Permalink</a></p>]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Kerberos (GSSAPI) Auth with OpenSSH in Cygwin on Windows]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2012/08/25/using-kerberos-gssapi-auth-with-openssh-in-cygwin-on-windows/"/>
<updated>2012-08-25T17:19:00-05:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2012/08/25/using-kerberos-gssapi-auth-with-openssh-in-cygwin-on-windows</id>
<category term="UNIX" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On my Windows machines at both work and home, I like to run <a href="http://www.cygwin.com/">Cygwin</a>
to get a UNIX-like environment on Windows: <code>screen</code>, <code>ssh</code>, <code>grep</code>, etc.
I use SSH&#39;s <a href="https://hkn.eecs.berkeley.edu/%7Edhsu/ssh_public_key_howto.html">public key authentication</a>
pretty extensively to get password-less authentication to make it dead-easy
(and quick!) to SSH around to different machines.</p>

<p>On some of the non-UNIX machines at work, I couldn&#39;t get SSH public-key auth
working, but those machines <em>do</em> support Kerberos auth (binding to Active
Directory). Based on my Google searches, all I could find were articles talking
about compiling OpenSSH from source to get a working Kerberos-enabled version
of OpenSSH on Cygwin. So, that made it sound like it would be a pain to get
this working.  But, after doing some more playing around, I found this was
actually easy to setup once you understand the various pieces. Since I couldn&#39;t
find any helpful information online when I first tried to get this working, I
figured I&#39;d write up what worked for me in case that helps other people.</p>

<!-- more -->

<h2>Installation</h2>

<ol>
<li>Install the <code>openssh</code> package.</li>
<li>Install the <code>heimdal</code> package, which supplies an implementation of the
   Kerberos tools. This gets you things like <code>kinit</code>, <code>klist</code>, etc.</li>
<li>You may want to configure your <code>/etc/krb5.conf</code> file to list a default realm
   so that you don&rsquo;t need to specify it when doing the <code>kinit</code> later on:
   
<figure class='code'><figcaption>/etc/krb5.conf </figcaption><div class='highlight'><table><td class='line-numbers' aria-hidden='true'><pre><div data-line='1' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='2' class='line-number'></div></pre></td><td class='main  sh'><pre><div class='line'><span class="o">[</span>libdefaults<span class="o">]</span>
</div><div class='line'>       <span class="nv">default_realm</span> <span class="o">=</span> REALM_NAME
</div></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

   Alternatively, rather than fiddling with <code>/etc/krb5.conf</code> on my Cygwin
   install, I opted to use the <code>KRB5&#95;CONFIG</code> environment variable (see the
   <code>kinit</code> manpage) to point to a <code>~/.krb5.conf</code> file instead to keep my
   Kerberos config confined to my <code>$HOME</code> directory (since I <a href="http://nynim.org/blog/2011/12/20/home-sweet-home">keepmy $HOME directory under version control</a>).</li>
<li>Modify your <code>~/.ssh/config</code> file to enable GSSAPI authentication:
   
<figure class='code'><figcaption>~/.ssh/config </figcaption><div class='highlight'><table><td class='line-numbers' aria-hidden='true'><pre><div data-line='1' class='line-number'></div></pre></td><td class='main  plain'><pre><div class='line'>GSSAPIAuthentication yes</div></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>
</li>
</ol>

<h2>Usage</h2>

<ul>
<li> Before you <code>ssh</code> to a remote machine where you want to use Kerberized credentials,
simply run <code>kinit</code> to acquire a new Kerberos ticket. (Pro tip: you can run <code>klist</code> to
list all your active Kerberos tickets and their expiration dates.)</li>
<li> With the <code>GSSAPIAuthentication</code> directive in your <code>.ssh/config</code> file, that should
enable GSSAPI authentication for free. There&#39;s also a <code>-K</code> param to the <code>ssh</code> command
which talks about enabling GSSAPI auth and forwarding, which I&#39;m not entirely sure
what that controls, but my guess is that it&#39;s for opting into GSSAPI auth mode if
you <strong>don&#39;t</strong> have that directive in your <code>.ssh/config</code> file.</li>
</ul>

<p>I hope this helps someone else who&#39;s trying to get Kerberized SSH working on Cygwin.
Happy SSH&#39;ing!</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[All-In-One Home File Server: VMware ESXi, OpenIndiana, and ZFS]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2012/06/04/all-in-one-home-file-server-vmware-esxi-openindiana-and-zfs/"/>
<updated>2012-06-04T21:25:00-05:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2012/06/04/all-in-one-home-file-server-vmware-esxi-openindiana-and-zfs</id>
<category term="Hardware" /><category term="Storage" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just over a year ago, I built a new home file-server since I was quickly
outgrowing my existing storage capacity. Rather than just dropping more HDD&#39;s
into the existing hardware I had running, I succumbed to geek techno-lust and
opted to explore new technologies: <strong>ZFS</strong> and <strong>VMWare ESXi</strong>.</p>

<!-- more -->

<h2>Going Virtualized</h2>

<p>Virtualization is huge in the enterprise-space these days. After talking with
some friends from work about what kind of virtualization strategies we&#39;re using
for our in-house datacenter, I became enticed by the idea of running a &ldquo;bare metal&rdquo;
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypervisor">hypervisor</a>: install virtualization
software as the primary OS on the physical hardware and spinning up VM&#39;s for
different logical needs.</p>

<p>Over the years, I&#39;ve accumulated a fair amount of old computers. Back in the day,
those extra computers gave me an opportunity to try-out new OSes/software: playing
with different Ubuntu configurations, tinkering with different *BSD flavors, etc.
But once my spare-time dried up, all that old computer hardware just became <em>clutter</em>
taking-up space and it seemed like such a pain to fire up an old computer just to
tinker with some new configuration.</p>

<p>So, going virtualizations held a lot of (obvious) appeal to me: minimize my physical
hardware (less power consumed, less physical space, etc) while letting me easily
tinker with new configurations.</p>

<h2>ZFS-Powered</h2>

<p>Based on <a href="http://nynim.org/blog/2011/03/05/zfs-the-last-word-in-filesystems/">previous research</a>,
I knew that I really wanted to move to some kind of <strong>ZFS-backed</strong> storage solution,
to protect/maintain the integrity of my ever-increasing digital collection.</p>

<p>After following the &ldquo;zfs-discuss&rdquo; mailing list for a few months, given my simple
home-needs a simple mirrored configuration (along with proper backups) seemed like
the <a href="http://constantin.glez.de/blog/2010/01/home-server-raid-greed-and-why-mirroring-still-best">best solution</a>.
If I need more space, I can expand horizontally: add another pair of drives (of
whatever size is appropriate) to expand my pool. It was this easy expansion
which pushed me towards a mirrored configuration rather than a RAID-Z style
configuration. The trouble with RAID-Z is that you can&#39;t add new devices to a
vdev after you&#39;ve initially created it; the only way to &ldquo;grow&rdquo; a RAID-Z vdev is
by replacing <strong>all</strong> of the individual drives (<em>one at a time, waiting for each
to resilver</em>) and setting the &ldquo;autoexpand&rdquo; property on the pool so that ZFS
will auto-expand the pool based on the new common maximum size of each of the
individual drives. But, that&#39;s a whole lot of moving parts (<em>pun intended</em>) and
replacing all the drives in the pool isn&#39;t quite my idea of easy expansion.
Mirroring just seems easier, given that I don&#39;t need lots of individual drives
for raw performance reasons.</p>

<h2>All-in-One Solution</h2>

<p>Somewhere along the line in my research, I stumbled upon <a href="http://www.napp-it.org/napp-it/all-in-one/index_en.html"><strong>napp-it</strong></a>,
which introduced me to this idea of an &ldquo;all-in-one&rdquo; fileserver: using VMWare
ESXi as a bare-metal hypervisor, having a Solaris-based VM running on the ESXi
datastore which will control the mass-storage ZFS pool, and then exporting an
NFS share back out to ESXi so that you can store the bulk of the VMs on
ZFS-backed storage. It&#39;s a bit complicated at first glance, but it performs
great (thanks to hardware-passthrough) and lets me easily manage the bulk of my
VMs on ZFS-backed storage.</p>

<p>To make use of ESXi&#39;s hardware-passthrough support, you need to run server-grade
hardware. For me, that meant going with an Xeon-based CPU with appropriate motherboard
chipset. But that also gave other server-grade wins like using ECC memory and IPMI
(easy remote-control of the console, which is <em>awesome</em>).</p>

<h2>Shopping List</h2>

<p>Here is the hardware I ended-up going with:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16819117225">Intel Xeon X3440 Lynfield 2.53GHz</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16813182211">Supermicro X8SIL-F-O</a></li>
<li>2x <a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16820139077">Kingston 4GB DDR3 ECC Unbuffered</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16816117157">Intel SASUC8I (LSI 1068E) SATA/SAS card</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16817151088">SeaSonic X650 Gold PSU</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16811352004">Fractal Design Define R3 Mid-Tower Case</a></li>
<li>2x <a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822145475">2TB Hitachi Deskstar 5K3000</a> (primary pool)</li>
<li>2x <a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822145475">2TB Hitachi Deskstar 5K3000</a> (backup pool)</li>
<li>2x <a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16822145475">2TB Hitachi Deskstar 5K3000</a> (off-site backup pool)</li>
</ul>

<p>The Xeon chipset was needed for some of the hardware passthrough features in
ESXi, e.g. passing through the HBA card directly to the Solaris-based VM so
that ZFS can have direct access to the physical drives.</p>

<p>The 650W power-supply ended-up being way more than I needed. The server uses
less than 100W when idle, though that PSU is still quite efficient even with
such low power draw.</p>

<h2>Looking Back</h2>

<p>The setup has been awesome so far. Even just getting to play around with
server-grade hardware has been an eye-opening experience. Being able to
remote-control the server, e.g. mounting an ISO remotely over the Java-based
client and installing the OS on the computer all without needing to hook-up a
keyboard or monitor, has been a revelation.  (<em>Goodbye old CRT monitor that I
used to keep around for my server closet!</em>)</p>

<p>I love the flexibility of ESXi. I have an Ubuntu VM for development/testing, a
FreeBSD VM for running Mediatomb (PS3 media-server), etc. It even let me play
around with different Solaris flavors while trying to figure out what OS I
wanted to use for the ZFS back-end. It&#39;s just so easy to spin-up new VMs to
test an idea or just to play around.</p>

<p>I started out using Solaris 11 Edition (free), which ran fine for the better
part of a year. I tried upgrading to Solaris 11/11 earlier this year only to
find that Solaris 11 apparently doesn&#39;t play nicely with ESXi. From there, I
jumped over to using <a href="http://openindiana.org/">OpenIndiana</a>, the open-source
spin-off from the now-defunct OpenSolaris lineage.</p>

<p>ZFS has been a huge win too. Taking nightly snapshots makes it dead-easy to
look back in time to see how day was several months ago. The snapshots also
make it easy to send the incremental differences to a backup pool. The built-in
CIFS server makes it dead-easy to mount the shares on Windows, and the
filesystem snapshots are easily accessible via the &ldquo;Previous Versions&rdquo; tab in
Windows Explorer. I also really love the idea of the &ldquo;pool&rdquo;. I can create
different filesystems to group/organize my data (e.g. photos vs. music vs.
backups), enable compression on a per-filesystem basis, set quotas per
filesystem, etc.</p>

<p>I really love the &ldquo;all-in-one&rdquo; idea: ZFS reliability combined with the
flexibility of VMWare ESXi.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[svn2svn: Replaying SVN History]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2012/02/01/svn2svn-replaying-svn-history/"/>
<updated>2012-02-01T21:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2012/02/01/svn2svn-replaying-svn-history</id>
<category term="Coding" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve found myself in a (potentially unique) situation where we have a
<em>gi-normous</em> <a href="http://subversion.apache.org/">Subversion</a> repository at work and
we&#39;ve been exploring ways on how to trim off some of the fat but still keep all
the logical history so that we could still use things like <code>svn blame</code> to
drill-down into code-history. Our central SVN repository is some 4-5 years old
and a whopping 300GB+ on-disk. (Yowza!) What we&#39;d really like to do is dump
just the <code>/trunk</code> history out to a new repo and roll forward with that, ditching
any historical baggage from old topic branches (<code>/branches</code>). The trouble is,
I haven&#39;t been able to find any tools to do this.</p>

<p>So, I ended-up writing my own tool to do this. But, first, some back-story&hellip;</p>

<!-- more -->

<h2>Existing Tools</h2>

<p>In doing some searches for variations around &ldquo;<em>svn repo filter</em>&rdquo;, I found a lot
of people pointing to the &ldquo;<a href="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/en/1.7/svn.ref.svndumpfilter.html">svndumpfilter</a>&rdquo;
utility as the tool-of-choice. Sadly, it doesn&#39;t seem to be quite &ldquo;smart&rdquo; enough
to do what I&#39;d like it to do. It seems to be aimed at (namely) filtering an
<code>svnadmin dump</code> stream, taking only certain paths in the SVN &ldquo;filesystem&rdquo;. That
works fine if you&#39;re trying to take an isolated folder/project from the repository,
but if that folder/project has ever been merged into from any paths <em>outside</em> of
the target filter path, then things fall apart. The &ldquo;trouble&rdquo; are the copy-from&#39;s&hellip;</p>

<p>For example, say that you have a repo with a typical trunk/tags/branches setup.
Say you create a new topic branch (e.g. <code>svn copy /trunk /branches/my-fix &amp;&amp; svn co /branches/my-fix</code>)
and happily work on your sandboxed branch. Say that you decide to rename some of
the pre-existing files/folders, so you run the appropriate <code>svn move</code> commands and
happily commit those changes to your branch. Once everything is working happily,
you go to merge these changes into <code>/trunk</code> and that all works great. After the
commmit, if you run a <code>svn log -v -l1 /trunk</code> to look at the details of the most
recent commit to trunk, you&#39;ll see something like this:
    A /trunk/Project/RenamedFolder (from /branches/my-fix/Project/RenamedFolder@12345)
&hellip;which only describes the (top-level) folder rename, not any add/modifications/renames/etc
that might have happened <em>inside</em> that folder on the branch. At the full repo-level,
SVN can get away with just doing a &ldquo;<code>svn copy</code>&rdquo; from the branch to trunk, so that
when you do an &ldquo;<code>svn log</code>&rdquo; on the new &ldquo;RenamedFolder&rdquo; path it will walk from trunk
back into that originating topic branch and follow the rename (copy or move) that
happened within.</p>

<p>The <code>svnadmin dump</code> will show the same &ldquo;copy-from&rdquo; action as <code>svn log -v</code> did,
since the dump stream will need to be able to recreate that same ancestry. When
<code>svndumpfilter</code> sees this, it throws up its hands and returns an error because
it doesn&#39;t know how to <em>recreate</em> the logical history that happened between
when that branch originally forked from trunk versus the final state of that branch.
That is, assuming the copy-from path even has any ancestry back to trunk&hellip;</p>

<h2>If You Want Something Done Right&hellip;</h2>

<p>In my searches, I had found a few folks that had hacked together there own
solutions. None of those quite fit my problem at hand, so naturally I decided
to start working on my own solution.</p>

<p>The closest fit I found was a project named &ldquo;<a href="http://code.google.com/p/svn2svn/">svn2svn</a>&rdquo;
hosted on Google Code. It had copied parts of the &ldquo;<a href="https://bitbucket.org/andialbrecht/hgsvn/overview">hgsvn</a>&rdquo;
project (<em>sychronizing between Mercurial and Subversion repositories</em>) and
slapped them together in a way that worked for the original author&#39;s needs.
It used &ldquo;<code>svn log</code>&rdquo; to walk the entire history of a given path in a source
repository and then manually replayed those changes to a working-copy of
some path in a target repository. Revision by revision, it would replay
the delta, recreating the history of just the source path in the target repo.
This was <em>oh-so-close</em> to what I wanted, except that it also didn&#39;t correctly
handle the copy-from case. And the repository I really wanted to replay was
<em>littered</em> with copy-from&#39;s, since I&#39;m trying to replay just the history from
<code>/trunk</code> and we create topic-branches for <em>everything</em>.</p>

<h2>Enter svn2svn</h2>

<p>So, I started with the <a href="http://code.google.com/p/svn2svn/">svn2svn</a> project,
got familiar with the code, and started hacking to extend the code to solve my
problem at hand.</p>

<p>The net-result is my own (nearly completely rewritten) take on the problem,
a project which I&#39;m also calling <strong><a href="http://nynim.org/code/svn2svn/">svn2svn</a></strong>.</p>

<p>I&#39;ve made several enhancements to the original script:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Full ancestry (copy-from) support.</strong> This was the tricky part. It took
several different iterations/rewrites to get something which worked for all
the different edge-cases. The general idea here is that we can use <code>svn log</code>
to walk backwards through the ancestry on a copy-from case: if we can trace
back our ancestry to same source path we&#39;re replaying, then we can do an <code>svn
copy</code> from that original parent and then do <code>svn export</code> to update the
contents of all the files to match the final copy-from verison. There&#39;s also
some extra recursion that needs to happen here, to handle cases where child
files got renamed inside of a parent-renamed folder. There are other
edge-cases like files getting replaced inside a parent-renamed folder.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Use revprops for source-tracking and resume support.</strong> Subversion has
revision properties, key+value pairs that are associated with a particular
revision/commit. I&#39;m setting some <code>svn2svn:*</code> rev-props to track the source
URL, source repository UUID (i.e. in case source URL now points at a
physically different repo), and source revision #. This is all needed for
proper resume support, since for the ancestry support we have to maintain a
mapping-table of source_rev -&gt; target_rev, so that when we find a copy-from
from some revision # in the source repo, we can map this to the equivalent
revision # in the target repo so we can do an equivalent <code>svn copy</code> command.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Better verbosity output, and optional debug output.</strong> As I was playing with
the rewrite, I quickly found I needed better debug output, to see which shell
commands were being run and ot display just general debug/status messages as
we do all this new complicate ancestry-walking logic. Bonus: the debugging
messages have colored output, using <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ANSI_escape_code#CSI_codes">ANSI escape
codes</a> which all
self-respecting terminal emulators should respect.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>All commits (including initial import) go through the same central
code-path, which means we could run a (client-side) pre-commit script to
scrub the contents of the target working-copy before each commit.</strong> This is
where the power of doing the manual replay of changes really starts to shine.
We have full control over the pending changes, which means that if your
original trunk history had some files which you didn&#39;t want to transition
into the new replayed repo then you could easily <code>svn rm</code> those files from
the working-copy before the commit happens. That could be as simple as
excluding certain fixed paths, but it could be a lot more flexible like
searching the entire working-copy tree and removing any files which match
a certain file-name. Heck, you could even modify the working-copy
file-contents at this point&hellip;or add brand-new files if you want. We&#39;re
<em>replaying</em> the SVN history here will full control of the target content,
so this opens a lot of interesting options.</p></li>
</ul>

<p>Check-out the <a href="http://nynim.org/code/svn2svn/">svn2svn project page</a> for more details.</p>

<p>Also, I have the project mirrored on <a href="https://github.com/tonyduckles/svn2svn">Github</a>
so please feel free to fork the project, send me issues/enhancements, or
send me pull-requests for any tweaks you&#39;ve made.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Sweet $HOME]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2011/12/20/home-sweet-home/"/>
<updated>2011-12-20T19:35:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2011/12/20/home-sweet-home</id>
<category term="UNIX" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://nynim.org/images/2011/12/img_Terminal.png" width="180" height="180">
About a year and a half ago, I stumbled upon Ryan Tomayko&#39;s &ldquo;<a href="https://github.com/rtomayko/dotfiles">dotfiles</a>&rdquo;
repository on Github. The moment I saw it, I thought it was a <em>great</em> idea:
the idea of managing all your <code>$HOME</code> directory &ldquo;dot-files&rdquo; in a Git repository.
That single idea led me on a personal crusade to better understand all the
different configuration files that live in your UNIX (<em>Linux, Mac OSX, etc.</em>)
home directory, and the end-result was creating my own &ldquo;<a href="https://github.com/tonyduckles/dotfiles">dotfiles</a>&rdquo;
Git repository for synchronizing/tracking/deploying my dot-files between the
various machines I work upon.</p>

<p>I learned a lot of neat stuff along the way, including some config options
which I never knew were there and some tricks which really optimized my
command-line shell experience.</p>

<!-- more -->

<h2>Using Git</h2>

<p>I found it to be a very natural fit to use Git to track the edits to my dot-files.
It makes it dead-easy to see what changes I&#39;ve made since the last commit and
easy to commit those changes and push them to a central Git repository.</p>

<p>Git also makes it dead-easy to &ldquo;bootstrap&rdquo; my dot-files environment into a
brand-new home directory:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption>Dotfiles bootstrap </figcaption><div class='highlight'><table><td class='line-numbers' aria-hidden='true'><pre><div data-line='1' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='2' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='3' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='4' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='5' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='6' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='7' class='line-number'></div></pre></td><td class='main  sh'><pre><div class='line'><span class="c"># Clone the repo into ~/dotfiles/</span>
</div><div class='line'>git clone git://github.com/tonyduckles/dotfiles.git dotfiles
</div><div class='line'><span class="c"># Move all the contents (including .git, but excluding the specal &quot;.&quot; and &quot;..&quot; directories)</span>
</div><div class='line'><span class="c"># into ~, overwriting any pre-existing files</span>
</div><div class='line'>mv dotfiles/.??* .
</div><div class='line'><span class="c"># Clean-up the now-orphaned ~/dotfiles/ directory</span>
</div><div class='line'>rm -rf dotfiles
</div></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

<h2>~/bin/</h2>

<p>Ryan has a <code>~/bin/</code> directory in his dot-files repo with all kinds of nifty
little utilities.</p>

<p>There&#39;s a bunch of great Git-related utilities in there, e.g.:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rtomayko/dotfiles/blob/rtomayko/bin/git-up">git-up</a> - Like <code>git-pull</code> but show a short and sexy log of changes immediately after merging (git-up) or rebasing (git-reup).</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rtomayko/dotfiles/blob/rtomayko/bin/git-incoming">git-incoming</a>/<a href="https://github.com/rtomayko/dotfiles/blob/rtomayko/bin/git-outgoing">git-outgoing</a> - Shows difference between the current branch vs. the upstream branch.</li>
</ul>

<p>And there&#39;s also some great general-purpose utilities in there, e.g.:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://betterthangrep.com/">ack</a> - A tool like <code>grep</code>, designed for programmers with large trees of heterogeneous source code. Very handy for recursive file-searching.</li>
</ul>

<h2>~/.gitconfig</h2>

<p>Ryan has lots of nifty tricks in his <code>.gitconfig</code> file, tying in short-cuts for
calling the helper utilities in <code>~/bin/</code>. Also, you can setup Git to use ANSI
colors for various sub-commands (diff, status), which is <em>very</em> handy.</p>

<h2>~/.inputrc</h2>

<p>There&#39;s a lot of neat options in the <code>.inputrc</code> file, for binding key-sequences
to various command-line options. For example:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption>.inputrc snippet </figcaption><div class='highlight'><table><td class='line-numbers' aria-hidden='true'><pre><div data-line='1' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='2' class='line-number'></div></pre></td><td class='main  sh'><pre><div class='line'>C-n: <span class="nb">history</span>-search-forward
</div><div class='line'>C-p: <span class="nb">history</span>-search-backward
</div></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

<p>&hellip;are the <strong>two single-most time-saving key-bindings</strong> that I stumbled upon. This
lets you type a partial command and then use <code>Ctrl-n</code> and <code>Ctrl-p</code> to
completion-match the rest of the line based on your command history. Awesome!</p>

<p>I find this incredibly useful to completion-match hostnames for <code>ssh</code> commands or other
longer commands which I often type. Completion-matching for-the-win!</p>

<h2>Vim: .vimrc and .vim/</h2>

<p>Before setting out on this project, I had used Vi some but hadn&#39;t really explored
(or understood) the full-power that was <a href="http://www.vim.org/">Vim</a>. Digging
into the <code>.vimrc</code> file, reading-up on all the various config options, and
digging into all the <code>~/.vim/</code> plugins which Ryan had was an eye-opening
experience. I came to realize just how much you could extend and customize
Vim to meet your needs. Simple things like getting syntax-highlighting
and color-schemes set by default made for an oh-so-much more pleasant
Vim experience.</p>

<p>This all led me to learning a lot more about Vim and becoming much more proficent
using Vim. It&#39;s now my text-based editor of choice. Once you get to know the
key-bindings and the various commands, the command-chaining that you can do
in Vim is incredibly powerful.</p>

<h2>Sharing is Fun!</h2>

<p>If you&#39;re at all interesting in learning more about customizing your Unix
shell environment, looking at other people&#39;s dot-files is a great learning
experience. And publishing your dot-files on Github is a great way to
share your shell-environment with the world so that others can learn
and explore.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Octopress!]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2011/12/19/hello-octopress/"/>
<updated>2011-12-19T21:53:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2011/12/19/hello-octopress</id>
<category term="Blog" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago I stumbled upon a neat project named <strong><a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a></strong>:
<blockquote><p>Octopress is an obsessively designed framework for Jekyll blogging. It’s easy to configure and easy to deploy. Sweet huh?</p><footer><strong>Octopress</strong> <cite><a href='https://github.com/imathis/octopress'>github.com/imathis/octopress/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Sweet indeed! The more I read about it, the more intrigued I became. After a
few hours spent exploring the code, importing the posts/pages from my Wordpress
install into Octopress, and tweaking the default theme to my taste, I&#39;ve taken
the jump and moved my site over to using the Octopress platform.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Octopress is a simple blogging platform aimed at hackers. It&#39;s built around the
<a href="http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> engine, which is the blog-aware static
site generator that powers <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a>.  The &ldquo;database&rdquo;
for the site is simply a collection of flat text files using
<a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a> (or Textile) mark-up. You
can setup either &ldquo;posts&rdquo; or &ldquo;pages&rdquo;, all as you&#39;d expect. When you&#39;re ready to
deploy, you use <code>Rakefile</code> automation to &ldquo;generate&rdquo; the static site files.</p>

<p>It also has a great default theme (IMHO) &ndash; very clean and simple &ndash; which was
actually my original attraction. It was only after reading more about the project
that I realized it had huge appeal to my geek-side too.</p>

<h2>Why Octopress?</h2>

<p>It was Matt Gemmell&#39;s &ldquo;<a href="http://mattgemmell.com/2011/09/12/blogging-with-octopress/">Blogging With Octopress</a>&rdquo;
post which resonated the most with me:
<blockquote><p>WordPress is excellent, but it’s over-featured for what I need, and its PHP/MySQL guts are opaque. I don’t really like the idea of all my writing being inside a big database either; it’s a single point of failure, and that makes me uneasy.</p><footer><strong>Matt Gemmell</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>For what I do with my website, Wordpress was overkill. It ended-up being
<em>Yet-Another-Thing-I-Needed-To-Maintain-Security-Patches-On&trade;</em>.</p>

<p>I was immediately attracted to the simplicity which Octopress provides: editing
pages and posts as plain-text text-files, all static files so no security-patches
or vulnerabilities to worry about, and easily portable and backup-able. It combines
a lot of things which I have grown to love: I can keep all my content in a Git
repository so that I can publish from multiple locations (<em>if need be</em>), I can
work on the site entirely in text (<code>vim</code> + <code>screen</code>), and it&#39;s dead easy to
deploy and backup.</p>

<h2>Migrating from Wordpress</h2>

<p>It really didn&#39;t take that long to migrate everything over to Octopress.</p>

<p>It took a few hours to get a cleaned-up import of my old Wordpress content.
Based on the recommendation of others, I used <a href="https://github.com/thomasf/exitwp">exitwp</a>
to create Jekyll-style posts based on my Wordpress content. This went fine for
the most part, but there were some parts in the Wordpress export file that I
needed to fiddle to keep the <code>exitwp</code> script from crashing. The end result
was that I had a directory full of simple <code>*.markdown</code> files which represented
all the content from my Wordpress site. I spent a few hours going through those
files and cleaning up the Markdown syntax until it matched what I wanted. Some
of my original Wordpress posts were a mixture of Wordpress mark-up and raw HTML,
and that threw the <code>exitwp</code> parser for a loop in some places. It did a great
job overall though.</p>

<p>From there, I spent some time looking through the guts of the Octopress source
code getting acquainted with things and seeing how I might be able to fiddle
with some of its inner fiddly-bits. It&#39;s written with native support for
customization, trying to keep a clear separation between the core &ldquo;code&rdquo; of
the site (<em>which can be overwritten during a future upgrade</em>) versus any
&ldquo;customization&rdquo; files which the user might make changes too. It&#39;s a fantastic
paradigm and one that you don&#39;t often see too much of in projects.</p>

<p>Last but not least, I spent some time tweaking the theme to my tasting (<em>&hellip;a
bit of pepper here, a bit of salt there&hellip;</em>). As I mentioned above, it natively
carves out files which are earmarked for user-customizations, where you can
tweak the CSS (SASS), colors, page/sidebar dimensions, etc. It&#39;s all just
extremely well-thought-out and a joy to use and extend.</p>

<h2>Ending Thoughts</h2>

<p>This has been a fun pet project for me.  It&#39;s the first time I&#39;ve used a Ruby environment.
It&#39;s also the first time I&#39;ve played with <a href="http://sass-lang.com/">SASS</a> (<code>*.scss</code>),
and boy is it going to be hard to go back to writing plain-old CSS.
SASS&#39;s <a href="http://sass-lang.com/docs/yardoc/Sass/Script/Functions.html">color functions</a>
are ridiculously slick: being able to do things like <code>desaturate(lighten($nav-bg, 8), 15)</code>
in a <code>*.scss</code> file is <em>awesome</em> and makes tweaking a site&#39;s color-scheme
oh-so-much easier.</p>

<p>I&#39;m a bit sad to have lost the lifestream (<a href="https://github.com/dcramer/wp-lifestream/">wp-lifestream</a>)
functionality from my old Wordpress site. But then again I&#39;m already doing
full exports of most of my lifestream&#39;d websites (Google Reader, Delicious),
so it might not be too hard to generate static lifestream pages using a
<code>cronjob</code> or something. That&#39;s a project for another day&hellip;</p>

<h2>Useful Links</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://mattgemmell.com/2011/09/12/blogging-with-octopress/">Blogging With Octopress</a> -
A fantastic and well-thought-out introduction and overview of Octopress.</li>
<li><a href="http://zanshin.net/2011/08/11/switching-to-octopress/">Switching to Octopress</a> -
A great end-to-end summary of the Wordpress-to-Octopress transition process.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.meatleasing.com/octopress-hidden-features/index.html">Octopress Hidden Features</a> -
Pointing out some of subtle features of Octopress.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/thomasf/exitwp">exitwp</a> -
Tool for converting Wordpress export XML to the Jekyll blog engine.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.vim.org/scripts/script.php?script_id=3835">vim-octopress</a> -
Vim syntax highlighting mode for Octopress-flavored <code>*.markdown</code> files.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[ZFS: The Last Word in Filesystems]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2011/03/05/zfs-the-last-word-in-filesystems/"/>
<updated>2011-03-05T18:56:01-06:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2011/03/05/zfs-the-last-word-in-filesystems</id>
<category term="Storage" /><category term="UNIX" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve been spending a lot of time lately reading-up on different options since
my current home file-server setup is slowly running out of disk-space. Sure, I
could just throw some new HDD&#39;s in there, but the inner-geek in me really
wants to setup a new system that has both redundancy and scalability &ndash;
something more robust and future-proof.</p>

<p>In reading through different online forums, the topic of ZFS-based systems
kept coming-up again and again. I had heard the term &ldquo;ZFS&rdquo; thrown around
before but I had never really spent the time to read-up on it. It&#39;s just
another filesystem, right? How fancy can it be?</p>

<p>Well, <strong>ZFS is just damn cool</strong>. ZFS is <em>lot</em> more than &ldquo;<em>just another
filesystem</em>&rdquo;&hellip;</p>

<!-- more -->

<ul>
<li>It&#39;s a
<a href="http://blogs.sun.com/bonwick/entry/rampant_layering_violation">filesystem, logical volume manager, and software RAID subsystem</a>
all wrapped-up into one end-to-end system.</li>
<li>It does <a href="http://blogs.sun.com/bonwick/entry/zfs_end_to_end_data">end-to-end checksums</a>,
making sure the raw data read off the physical disk matches the same data
that was previously written to disk.</li>
<li>It is a transactional file system, which guarantees a consistent on-disk
data-state even with catastrophic failures like a power loss.</li>
<li>You can do data scrubbing online, as opposed to the normal Linux solution
of ext2/ext3/ext4 where you can only &ldquo;fsck&rdquo; a filesystem offline.</li>
<li>It uses a copy-on-write strategy which makes doing filesystem snapshot&#39;ing
a breeze. For example, you could setup a cronjob to take nightly snapshots
of your filesystem to facilitate incremental backups, i.e. allowing you to
go back in time and recover old-states of files.</li>
<li>It has <a href="http://blogs.sun.com/bonwick/entry/raid_z">RAID-Z support</a>, which
is similar to RAID-5/RAID-6 except without the potentially-fatal
&ldquo;<em>RAID-5 write hole</em>&rdquo; problem, in part thanks to the copy-on-write strategy.</li>
<li>You can <a href="http://dlc.sun.com/osol/docs/content/ZFSADMIN/gbchx.html">replicate ZFS filesystems</a>
(<code>zfs send</code> and <code>zfs receive</code>), snapshots and all, making it dead-easy to
backup ZFS filesystems to remote machines.</li>
</ul>

<p>Very, very cool stuff! The more I read about it, the more I wanted it for my
next-generation file-server solution. In particular, I really love the idea of
end-to-end checksums. I want to make darn sure that the OS can realize when
the disks are serving up garbage-data or if somehow bits have mysteriously
been corrupted on-disk (as unlikely as that might be).</p>

<p>In reading about all these various historical problems that ZFS sets out to
address, I&#39;m really surprised that more OSes haven&#39;t tried to adopt superior
filesystem technology. The classic problem for so many Windows-users seems to
be that their installs get &ldquo;corrupt&rdquo;, likely usually due to folks forcibly
powering-off their computers before the hard-drives have a chance to flush
their write-buffer to disk. And then folks get to cope with BSOD&#39;s or broken
Windows installs. Sad times for everyone. Filesystems seem like such a
foundational part of the OS that you&#39;d expect companies would spend the time
to make them as robust as possible. I read some rumors that Apple was planning
to incorporate ZFS into OSX a few years back, but apparently that fell apart
for some reason. Sad&hellip;</p>

<p>Kudos to the Sun folks for designing such a fantastic filesystem and then
open-sourcing it!</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Backup your Google Apps (or Gmail) e-mail over IMAP using imapsync]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2010/08/08/backup-your-google-apps-or-gmail-e-mail-over-imap-using-imapsync/"/>
<updated>2010-08-08T00:35:18-05:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2010/08/08/backup-your-google-apps-or-gmail-e-mail-over-imap-using-imapsync</id>
<category term="E-mail" /><category term="Storage" /><category term="UNIX" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have confidence in Google&#39;s ability to keep their e-mail service up-and-
running and keep proper backups of data, but my e-mail history is <em>my</em> data
and I like to have my own copy of it. Since Google provides access to your
Google Apps (and Gmail) e-mail over IMAP, you can do all kinds of things using
standard tools, e.g. synchronize your Gmail e-mail to a local mailbox using
IMAP.</p>

<p>I run an Ubuntu box at home and it was easy to install the <code>dovecot-imapd</code>
package to get an IMAP server installed. Since my box is behind my
router/firewall, I&#39;m wasn&#39;t that concerned with tweaking Dovecot&#39;s default
configuration, but I&#39;m sure you could fiddle with the config to ensure that
Dovecot only binds to <code>127.0.0.1</code>.</p>

<p>From there, it&#39;s just a matter of using <code>imapsync</code>, just like I ended-up
using previously to
<a href="http://nynim.org/blog/2010/08/07/moving-e-mail-from-gmail-to-google-apps-over-imap-using-imapsync/">initially transfer all my e-mail to my Google Apps account</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Here&#39;s the script:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class='highlight'><table><td class='line-numbers' aria-hidden='true'><pre><div data-line='1' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='2' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='3' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='4' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='5' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='6' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='7' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='8' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='9' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='10' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='11' class='line-number'></div></pre></td><td class='main  sh'><pre><div class='line'><span class="c"># Sync e-mail from &quot;username@yourdomain.com&quot; to localhost, using IMAP</span>
</div><div class='line'> imapsync --host1 imap.gmail.com --user1 username@yourdomain.com
</div><div class='line'>          --passfile1 /path/to/gmail_mirror.passfile1 <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>          --host2 localhost --user2 username
</div><div class='line'>          --passfile2 /path/to/gmail_mirror.passfile2 <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>          --ssl1 <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>          --useheader <span class="s1">&#39;Message-Id&#39;</span> --skipsize --allowsizemismatch <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>          --syncinternaldates --noauthmd5 -nofoldersizes<span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>          --split1 100 --split2 100 <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>          --regextrans2 <span class="s1">&#39;s/\[Gmail\]/username\@somedomain/&#39;</span> <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>          --include <span class="s2">&quot;All Mail|Sent Mail&quot;</span> --delete2 --expunge2
</div></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

<p>The <code>--regextrans2</code> option rewrites IMAP folder-names on-the-fly, so that my
local IMAP folder structure can be different than the structure on Gmail&#39;s
server. For example, the top Gmail IMAP folder is <code>[Gmail]</code> which wasn&#39;t all
that useful for me, so instead I rewrote that top-level folder to be
<code>username@somedomain</code> so that the local folder name (e.g. in <code>~/mail/</code>) would
match the source e-mail address.</p>

<p>You can also use the <code>--include</code> option to decide which IMAP folders to copy.
I opted to just copy &ldquo;All Mail&rdquo; and &ldquo;Sent Mail&rdquo;, which gives me a copy of all
my mail but doesn&#39;t preserve any information about the labels I might have had
assigned to those messages in Gmail.</p>

<p>The initial copy will definitely take a few hours (or more), depending on how
much e-mail you have in your Gmail account. But this works great for me and
stores the mail in &ldquo;mbox&rdquo; format locally so I can even access the mail locally
via mutt/alpine/etc.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving E-Mail from Gmail to Google Apps over IMAP using imapsync]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2010/08/07/moving-e-mail-from-gmail-to-google-apps-over-imap-using-imapsync/"/>
<updated>2010-08-07T23:31:49-05:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2010/08/07/moving-e-mail-from-gmail-to-google-apps-over-imap-using-imapsync</id>
<category term="E-mail" /><category term="Storage" /><category term="UNIX" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two years ago, I transitioned from using regular Gmail (i.e. &ldquo;<a href="mailto:...@gmail.com">&hellip;@gmail.com</a>&rdquo;)
to setting up Google Apps for &ldquo;nynim.org&rdquo; (i.e. &ldquo;<a href="mailto:...@nynim.org">&hellip;@nynim.org</a>&rdquo;). I had found
the following article back then which gave me helpful hints on how to use
<code>imapsync</code> to push data to my new Google Apps e-mail address:</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://gemal.dk/blog/2008/04/08/completed_the_gmail_migration/">http://gemal.dk/blog/2008/04/08/completed<em>the</em>gmail_migration/</a></strong></p>

<p>I adapted that script for my own needs, and I was able to successfully copy
all the mail from my regular Gmail account to my new Google Apps account.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Here is the final script I ended-up with:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class='highlight'><table><td class='line-numbers' aria-hidden='true'><pre><div data-line='1' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='2' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='3' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='4' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='5' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='6' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='7' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='8' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='9' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='10' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='11' class='line-number'></div><div data-line='12' class='line-number'></div></pre></td><td class='main  sh'><pre><div class='line'><span class="c">#!/bin/sh</span>
</div><div class='line'> <span class="c"># Copy all e-mail from source@gmail.com to target@yourdomain.com (Google Apps)</span>
</div><div class='line'> imapsync <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>   --host1 imap.gmail.com --port1 993 --user1 <span class="nb">source</span>@gmail.com <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>   --passfile1 /path/to/gmail_mirror.passfile1 --ssl1 <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>   --host2 imap.gmail.com --port2 993 --user2 target@yourdomain.com <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>   --passfile2 /path/to/gmail_mirror.passfile2 --ssl2 <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>   --useheader <span class="s1">&#39;Message-Id&#39;</span> --skipsize <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>   --syncinternaldates --noauthmd5 -nofoldersizes <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>   --split1 100 --split2 100 <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>   --maxage 50 <span class="se">\</span>
</div><div class='line'>   --regexmess <span class="s1">&#39;s/Delivered-To: source\@gmail.com/Delivered-To: target\@yourdomain.com/g&#39;</span>
</div></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

<p>The <code>--syncinternaldates</code>, <code>--useheader &#39;Message-Id&#39;</code>,
and <code>--skipsize</code> options are all recommended by the imapsync FAQ
(search for &ldquo;Gmail&rdquo;):</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://www.linux-france.org/prj/imapsync/FAQ">http://www.linux-france.org/prj/imapsync/FAQ</a></strong></p>

<p>I opted to use the <code>--passfile1/passfile2</code> options rather than passing in a
plain-text password in via a command-line param for two reasons: first because
anyone with access to your system can use <code>ps</code> to view active processes and
hence would see your password plain-as-day; second because it just better
abstracts the script-logic from the password-text, and we can control the
file-permissions of those password files.</p>

<p>All your Gmail labels should sync-over <em>automagically</em>. Since this is going
Google-to-Google, because Google presents labels as separate IMAP folders in
their Gmail IMAP implementation, the process above should sync and preserve
all your Gmail labels for free.</p>

<p>It&#39;s been a two years since I&#39;ve used this script, but I seem to remember it
working pretty painlessly. I wanted to share it here for anyone else who might
be looking to do this same thing.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[What to Wear-a?]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2009/12/28/what-to-wear-a/"/>
<updated>2009-12-28T23:20:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2009/12/28/what-to-wear-a</id>
<category term="Humor" /><category term="Quick Notes" /><category term="Video Games" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kotaku.com/5430723/what-to-wear+a"><img class="" src="http://nynim.org/images/2010/08/500x_marioscloset.jpg"></a></p>

<p>(<em>via <a href="http://kotaku.com/5430723/what-to-wear+a">kotaku.com</a></em>)</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Autocomplete Me]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2009/11/22/autocomplete-me/"/>
<updated>2009-11-22T23:21:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2009/11/22/autocomplete-me</id>
<category term="Humor" /><category term="Quick Notes" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://autocompleteme.com/"><img class="" src="http://nynim.org/images/2010/08/autocompletemecom-howtoraise.jpg"></a></p>

<p>(<em>via <a href="http://autocompleteme.com/">autocompleteme.com</a></em>)</p>

<p>Google auto-complete hilarity.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[GeoDefense]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2009/11/13/geodefense/"/>
<updated>2009-11-13T19:57:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2009/11/13/geodefense</id>
<category term="Quick Notes" /><category term="Video Games" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.appolicio%20us.com/games/apps/24846-geodefense-lite-critical-thought-games"><img class="" src="http://nynim.org/images/2010/08/geodefense_1250610916.jpg"></a></p>

<p>(<em>via <a href="http://www.appolicious.com/games/apps/24846-geodefense-lite-critical-thought-games">appolicious.com</a></em>)</p>

<p>After hearing some rave-reviews from various places over the past few days,
I picked-up GeoDefense for the iPhone this evening. Wow, it’s a blast! Nice
balanced game-play, good amount of challenge, great graphics. Well worth
the $2.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nynim.org: New & Improved]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2008/12/20/nynim-org-new-improved/"/>
<updated>2008-12-20T12:04:51-06:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2008/12/20/nynim-org-new-improved</id>
<category term="Blog" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve resurrected my nearly abandoned website and breathed new life into it!
I&#39;m now running <strong><a href="http://www.sweetcron.com/">SweetCron</a></strong>, an open-source
project for rolling you own personalized lifestream.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>I find that I don&#39;t always have the inspiration or motivation to write blog
posts that often, but I do have a Web 2.0 foot-print that other people might
want to watch, whether it be sharing interesting news tidbits on
<a href="http://www.google.com/reader/shared/09011817463293213634">Google Reader</a> to
bookmarking useful webpages on <a href="http://delicious.com/tduckles">Del.icio.us</a>,
to what songs I love on <a href="http://www.last.fm/user/tonyduckles">Last.fm</a>.</p>

<p>Hence, the birth of this lifestream: all my various online activities
aggregated and presenting in a unified &ldquo;lifestream&rdquo;. This gives others an easy
way to check-out what I&#39;m up to. If you have any comments or feedback, drop me
an e-mail!</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Maintaining Online Identities]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2007/09/11/maintaining-online-identities/"/>
<updated>2007-09-11T20:47:44-05:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2007/09/11/maintaining-online-identities</id>
<category term="Security" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I stumbled across this neat site called <a href="http://www.clipperz.com/">Clipperz</a> a
few weeks back. On the surface, it&#39;s &ldquo;<em>a free and anonymous online password
manager</em>&rdquo;. This was immediately interesting to me because I&#39;d really like to
find a (secure!) web-based password manager.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>More and more lately, I&#39;ve been
trying to find web apps that can replace the desktop applications I use on a
daily basis. It&#39;s just so incredibly convenient to have the portability to be
able to do everything you need from inside a web-browser, and more importantly
to have the persistent-state data stored on the server-side rather than on
each individual machine I use throughout the day. I&#39;m already a huge fan of
webapps like <a href="http://del.icio.us/tduckles">del.icio.us</a> (<em>for tracking all my
bookmarks</em>) and <a href="http://www.google.com/reader/">Google Reader</a> (<em>for all my
RSS aggregation and reading needs</em>), and finding a web-based password manager
would be ideal. It really becomes a chore remembering what username or e-mail
address I registered with at various websites: Amazon, eBay, Newegg, Google,
Yahoo, credit cards, travel sites, online bill pay, banks, etc. (Oy!) It&#39;s
just a lot of identities to juggle. I&#39;ve thought about using
<a href="http://keepass.info/">KeePass</a> or something, but that&#39;s a desktop app and I&#39;d
have to keep my database in-sync between work and home.</p>

<p>What really interested me about Clipperz is their claim at being a &ldquo;zero-
knowledge&rdquo; web-application: they only store encrypted data on their server-
side, and use Javascript to decrypt the data client-side based on the username
and password which you supply. Your password is never sent to the server at
all; it&#39;s merely used to decrypt the data locally. That&#39;s a pretty slick idea,
IMO. But, I&#39;m also a little nervous about trusting some third-party website
will all my personal sensitive online account information. So, I&#39;m tempted to
sit down and write my own webapp to recreate that wheel, except that it&#39;s all
code I can vouch for and know that it&#39;s not secretly sending my data off to
some third-party site. You can already find open-source Javascript-based
implementations of the various crypto algorithms that I&#39;d need to use. And it
seems like a simple AJAX-based webapp to save/load data from the server.</p>

<p>Also really intriguing is Clipperz&#39; one-click-sign-in feature. They have a
Javascript bookmark which pulls HTML FORM information off a given login page
and then allows you to link the various FORM INPUT fields with the appropriate
data-fields on the &ldquo;card&rdquo; for that website (e.g. username, password). The one-
click sign-in then just has to do a HTTP POST to the desired web-address with
the correct FORM data to act just like the real login page. It&#39;s simple
enough, but that seems like the real time-saver here. Not only could you have
a webapp which stores all your personal data, but it also provides a quick
launchpad to login any site you need. That just takes it a step further and
makes the webapp almost a blackbox: you don&#39;t really <em>need</em> to know what your
username and password is anymore because the webapp database knows it and can
feed it to the target website&#39;s login form for you.</p>

<p>This just seems like a really awesome idea, and I&#39;m really tempted to just use
Clipperz natively so that I don&#39;t have to re-invent the wheel, but I&#39;m still
just nervous about using someone else&#39;s website as a database to store all my
personal sensitive data. It&#39;s basically just a trust issue, and I don&#39;t think
I have any good reason to trust that their Javascript code will never do
anything malicious. I&#39;d much rather control the data myself on my private
webserver. If only Clipperz was a SourceForge project&hellip; ;)</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Off-Site Backups...?]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2007/09/11/simple-off-site-backups/"/>
<updated>2007-09-11T20:23:38-05:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2007/09/11/simple-off-site-backups</id>
<category term="Storage" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I&#39;ve been consumed with the idea of getting more serious about backing-
up all the data I have. I tend to be a digital pack-rat: my music collection,
digital photos I&#39;ve taken, all the songs I&#39;ve ever recorded, various tarballs
filled with code-stuffs for college projects I did, etc. There&#39;s a wealth of
nostalgia there, and I realized that I really wouldn&#39;t want to lose a lot of
that stuff.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>I already use a quasi-RAID system: I have two identical hdd&#39;s in my file-
server box and I rsync the &ldquo;master&rdquo; drive to the &ldquo;slave&rdquo; drive every so often.
Not only does this provide me some amount of rollback-ness (i.e. because I
only rsync so often), but the decision to not RAID-mirror the drives was
intentional: if the filesystem or partition table on the RAID somehow became
corrupted, all my data could be lost.</p>

<p>But&hellip;what if my house burns down? (*gasp* Oh noes!!) Yes, that would be sad
indeed! So, rather than just providing a single layer of redundancy locally,
if I really want to invest in the survival of my important data, I really need
to spread that data around; I need to diversify.</p>

<p>I&#39;ve looked around at various web-based back-up solutions like
<a href="http://aws.amazon.com/s3">Amazon&#39;s S3 service</a>, but those don&#39;t seem very optimal for me
because of the amount of data I want to backup (~150GB) and because it seems
like it would be a PITA to do a full restore over my home cable internet pipe.
Not to mention the monthly fees, paying someone else to store my data safe and
sound. But, dare I trust my important (and partially sensitive) data to a
stranger?</p>

<p>Currently, I&#39;m tempted by a seemingly simple solution: just get an external
USB hdd, mirror my data once locally, and then throw it at a friend&#39;s house
and use rsync to keep it up-to-date. The main cost involved is the cost of the
new hdd; there&#39;s no monthly fee because I already need to pay for my internet-
access. And I can even return the favor by hosting drives on my end too. And
this could even be expanded to a multiple people, if you wanted to back-up
your data in multiple off-sites. This seems almost too easy to me, but it
seems perfectly effective. Anything, it&#39;s making use of the hidden geek-
factor: you&#39;re a geek and you have geek friends, so why not make the most of
it and use them for geeky endeavors like helping each other backup each
other&#39;s data? ;)</p>

<p>The main problem I have with this plan is that my data wouldn&#39;t be encrypted
at all. I&#39;m not sure how paranoid I really need to be about my friends
snooping around my data. Though, I think this is basically the general idea
as: what would happen if someone stole your computer? So, that&#39;s really more
an argument that I should be locally encrypting my data so that even if prying
eyes were to get at my local/master copy, they still wouldn&#39;t be able to do
much with it.</p>

<p>Has anyone else given thought to getting more serious about backing up their
data?</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Minesweeper: The Movie]]></title>
<link href="http://kotaku.com/gaming/clips/minesweeper-the-movie-286639.php"/>
<updated>2007-08-06T22:03:31-05:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2007/08/06/minesweeper-the-movie</id>
<category term="Humor" /><category term="Quick Notes" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The guys over at College Humor have done it again, creating a faux movie
trailer for
<a href="http://kotaku.com/gaming/clips/minesweeper-the-movie-286639.php">Minesweeper: The Movie</a>.
It&#39;s a hilarious mishmash of awful action-movie stereotypes.</p>
<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://nynim.org/blog/2007/08/06/minesweeper-the-movie/">&#9875; Permalink</a></p>]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[del.icio.us director]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2007/05/19/del-icio-us-director/"/>
<updated>2007-05-19T23:23:24-05:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2007/05/19/del-icio-us-director</id>
<category term="Web" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, somewhere along the line&hellip;I became a geek. I started using multiple
computers, not just between home/work/school/etc., but even multiple computers
at home. (<em>Though, I mainly use my MacBook for all my casual web-surfing needs
these days at home&hellip;</em>) I was always annoyed by having different bookmarks on
the different computers I used, which meant frustration when I had to remember
which computer I bookmarked that useful such-and-such on. I wanted a way to
have a centralized webpage for my bookmarks and hence could access from
wherever I was. So, inspired by
<a href="http://24ways.org/2005/edit-in-place-with-ajax">an entry on 24ways.org</a>, I created one. It
was my little pet project, and it was good&hellip;</p>

<p>Then I found out that someone else had already done the same thing and they
had done it better. Enter <a href="http://del.icio.us/tduckles">del.icio.us</a>. (<em>Ooh,
the pretty pretty tag-clouds! Yes, my tag-cloud is quite delicious indeed&hellip;</em>)
Tags are such a simple concept, but oh-so effective. It just makes so much
sense to have a webapp where you save bookmarks and can assign arbitrary tags
to each entry. del.icio.us then makes it very easy to navigate around your
list of links by tags, even providing nifty &ldquo;easy&rdquo; URLs like
<a href="http://del.icio.us/tduckles/madison">http://del.icio.us/tduckles/madison</a>,
which shows me everything I&#39;ve tagged with &ldquo;madison&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Even better, people out there have written even slicker tools to access and
navigate around your del.icio.us bookmarks.
&lt;!&ndash; more &ndash;&gt;
John Vey wrote this amazingly cool
tool called <a href="http://johnvey.com/features/deliciousdirector/">del.icio.us direc.tor</a>.
In it&#39;s native form, it&#39;s meant to be a bookmarklet which you use at api.del.icio.us after
you&#39;ve done all your HTTP-Auth stuff, so that the JavaScript code doesn&#39;t need
to worry about auth when trying to access your bookmarks.</p>

<p>Not only is this a uber-slick UI for navigating around your tag-tree and for
quickly finding a link based on (real-time!) searching, but the page itself
also goes into the design and architecture of direc.tor. This was a really
fascinating read for me, from a web-dev perspective. What really blew my mind
about this is the whole concept of using AJAX methods to grab the del.icio.us
XML DOM, and then use XSLT and XPath features which are built-in to most
modern browsers to do all the searching in real-time on the client-side. So,
really, the whole bottom pane of direc.tor is the output of an XSTL on the
del.icio.us XML DOM of your bookmarks. I had never realized that you could do
XSLT and XPath operations via Javascript before. This was a watershed moment
for me, because a whole new perspective on web-development opened up for me:
you could use XMLHttpRequest to grab an XML document, and then use Javascript
to do an XSLT to transform that XML data into HTML or whatever presentation-
layer you wanted. In the past, I had always only thought of AJAX calls
returning some chunk of HTML which you could then insert somewhere into the
document DOM.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Reader]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2007/05/19/google-reader/"/>
<updated>2007-05-19T21:46:18-05:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2007/05/19/google-reader</id>
<category term="Web" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really dig the whole web-based RSS aggregator/reader thing. For the past
year or so, I&#39;ve been using <a href="http://www.reblog.org/">reBlog</a> on my Linux box
at home. It had it&#39;s quirks, but it was great to use.</p>

<p>Enter <strong><a href="http://www.google.com/reader/">Google Reader</a></strong>. Being the show-off&#39;s
they are, Google has created a fantastic RSS reader web-app. I&#39;ve ditched my
home-based reBlog setup for using Google Reader for all my RSS feed reading
needs. Here are the things which really won me over:</p>

<!-- more -->

<ul>
<li>Super-slick UI, with fantastic keyboard navigation support.</li>
<li>Nifty AJAX tricks, like only loading enough items into the ListView to fit
on screen initially and then fetching more as you scroll down. (<em>Of course,
they do this for performance reasons, but it&#39;s still implemented very cleanly
and just &ldquo;feels&rdquo; nice.</em>)</li>
<li>You can &ldquo;star&rdquo;/flag entries that are useful, and then go back and look at
all the articles you&#39;ve flagged. It remembers the timestamp of when you
flagged the entry, which I find handy. (<em>Though most useful links I consume
in a <a href="http://del.icio.us/tduckles">del.icio.us</a>-fashion these days&hellip;</em>)</li>
<li>You can easily sort either by Oldest or Newest, and it saves that preference
on each &ldquo;view&rdquo; (i.e. viewing entries from just one feed vs all entries) you have.</li>
<li>Has an &ldquo;infinite&rdquo; scrollback feature, to allow you to scroll backwards through
all the posts which Google has ever fetched for that feed.</li>
<li>It&#39;s free. ;)</li>
</ul>

<p>I would definitely recommend Google Reader to anyone that uses a fat-client
RSS reader/aggregator, especially if you want something that does the
aggregating 24-7 for you and is accessible from any computer.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Street Fighter: The Later Years]]></title>
<link href="http://www.collegehumor.com/tag:streetfighterthelateryears"/>
<updated>2006-11-27T22:43:12-06:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2006/11/27/street-fighter-the-later-years</id>
<category term="Humor" /><category term="Quick Notes" /><category term="Video Games" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don&#39;t know about you, but I remember playing a fair amount of
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Street_fighter#Street_Fighter_II">Street Fighter 2</a> back
in the day. College Humor is running this hilarious
<a href="http://www.collegehumor.com/tag:streetfighterthelateryears">series</a>, looking
into the lives of the Street Fighter combatants&hellip;10 years later. *insert
suspenseful music here!*</p>
<p><a rel="bookmark" href="http://nynim.org/blog/2006/11/27/street-fighter-the-later-years/">&#9875; Permalink</a></p>]]></content>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      




<title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefly & Fan Documentary DVD]]></title>
<link href="http://nynim.org/blog/2006/07/19/firefly-fan-documentary-dvd/"/>
<updated>2006-07-19T21:17:05-05:00</updated>
<id>http://nynim.org/blog/2006/07/19/firefly-fan-documentary-dvd</id>
<category term="Entertainment" />

      <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally succumbed to recommendations of friends and picked-up the Firefly TV
series on DVD&hellip;and it definitely didn&#39;t fail to impress. It&#39;s the best sci-fi
show I&#39;ve seen in a long time. It reminds me of ST:TNG in some ways, in so
much as it&#39;s very character-driven, with engaging characters who are developed
very nicely. I would certainly recommend it to any sci-fi fans who haven&#39;t had
a chance to see it yet.</p>

<p>The fan community for Firefly seems to be alive and strong, and it looks like
a <a href="http://www.donetheimpossible.com/">fan-compiled Firefly documentary</a> is on
the verge of being released. I&#39;m still debating picking it up&hellip; I know I can
get fanatical about some things, but I&#39;m not sure if I&#39;m too that point with
Firefly yet. I certainly wish that the TV series hadn&#39;t been cancel mid-1st-
season.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://www.donetheimpossible.com/">http://www.donetheimpossible.com/</a></strong></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>
